Guide to the Allan R. Holmberg collection on Peru, circa 1946-1966.
Holmberg, Allan R., collection on Peru, circa 1946-1966
- Series I. Cornell Peru Project (Accession 1)
  - Visual Materials
    - Photographs
      - Aerial photo of Quebrada Honda, August 30, 1948; RMC2004_5236; Gelatin silver print (Mapcase-folder 14)
        1948 aerial photograph image of Quebrada Honda landscape dated 30-8-48. Photograph also has inscription number 25 24 756 in upper right corner.
      - Vicos Artisan weaving on a loom, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5237; Gelatin silver print (Box 57)
      - Vicos boy, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5238; Gelatin silver print (Box 57)
      - Two Vicos women, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5239; Gelatin silver print (Box 57)
      - Vicosinos at the mill, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5240; Gelatin silver print (Box 57)
        Several men and women around the stone mill.
      - Preparing raspadilla (shaved ice), circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5241; Gelatin silver print (Box 57)
        Vicos man shaving block of ice while other sit around him eating the cool treat.
      - At the cemetery, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5242; Gelatin silver print (Box 57)
        Man arranges flowers and crosses on a grave while others grieve.
      - Funeral Procession Musicians, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5243; Gelatin silver print (Box 57)
      - Funeral Procession, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5244; Gelatin silver print (Box 57)
        Man carrying casket, funeral musicians, grieving women.
      - Funeral and mourning, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5245; Gelatin silver print (Box 57)
        Mourning men holding candles kneel in front of a coffin.
      - Army reservists standing at attention, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5246; Gelatin silver print (Box 57)
      - Technician teaching the use of a motor to a Vicos peasant, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5247; Gelatin silver print (Box 57)
      - Vicos hacienda, 1951; VC00273; Gelatin silver print (Box 57)
      - Vicos main plaza, 1951; VC00345; Gelatin silver print (Box 57)
      - Vicos hacienda, 1952; VC00279; Gelatin silver print (Box 57)
      - Holmberg instructs staff, 1952; VC01162; Gelatin silver print (Box 57)
      - Vicos school children play chase, undated; VC00080b; Gelatin silver print (Box 57)
      - Vicosinos in Marcara market, Undated; VC00662; Gelatin silver print (Box 57)
      - Military conscripts at Carhuas, 1952; VC01064; Gelatin silver print (Box 57)
      - System of new terraces, 1952; VC00464; Gelatin silver print (Box 57)
      - Vicos main plaza, 1951; VC00347; Gelatin silver print (Box 57)
      - Modern terraced field, ca. 1950-1965; VC01998; Gelatin silver print (Box 57)
      - Vicos school, 1951; VC00353; Gelatin silver print (Box 57)
      - Ruined buildings of Vicos hacienda, ca. 1950-1965; VC01994; Gelatin silver print (Box 57)
      - Peasant homestead, 1952; VC00337; Gelatin silver print (Box 57)
      - Wheat field, 1952; VC00246; Gelatin silver print (Box 57)
      - Vicosino sleeps off the effects of fiesta, 1951; VC00295; Gelatin silver print (Box 57)
      - Fight during the burial ceremony, 1952; VC01037; Gelatin silver print (Box 57)
      - Vicos hacienda, 1951; VC00275; Gelatin silver print (Box 57)
      - Cemetery wall, 1952; VC00451; Gelatin silver print (Box 57)
      - Six mounted black and white prints, ca. 1950s; Gelatin silver print (Box 57)
      - Guillen-Vicos photographs, 2-inch x 2-inch black-and-white prints; Abraham Guillen (Box 19)
    - Slides
      - Vicos church, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5248; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Vicosinos at the door of the church, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5249; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Vicos crowd in front of the church, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5250; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Allan Holmberg and school teacher at Vicos, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5251; Color slide (Box 19)
        Huascaran, Peruvian highest mountain is in the background.
      - Crosses at Vicos, typically placed on top of hills, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5252; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Woman of Vicos dressed for a wedding, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5253; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Vicosinos at trial (?) wedding, 1951; RMC2004_5254; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Young Woman of Vicos in Typical Dress, 1958; RMC2004_5255; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Cornell Peru Project Staff group picture, 1960; RMC2004_5256; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Quiet sunset in Vicos, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5257; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Congregation in front of the church at daybreak, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5258; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Characteristic Vicos adobe house, 1958; RMC2004_5259; Color slide; Abraham Guillen (Box 19)
      - Vicosino female in typical dress, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5260; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Vicos male in typical dress, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5261; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Two Vicos women spinning wool, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5262; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Harvesting maize, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5263; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Potato harvest in Vicos, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5264; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Wooden plow used by Vicosinos, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5265; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Plowing rocky fields, Vicos, Ancash, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5266; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Trigo (wheat) harvest, July 1954; RMC2004_5267; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Barbecho (fallow), September 1955; RMC2004_5268; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Thrashing quinua, September 1955; RMC2004_5269; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Cebada (barley) harvest, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5270; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Era de cebada (barley thrashing floor), circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5271; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Peasants at the barley thrashing floor, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5272; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Vicos peasants loading barley, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5273; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Vicos peasants winnowing barley, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5274; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Winnowing barley, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5275; Color slide (Box 19)
        See also ID Number: RMC2004_5274
      - Communal harvest work, 1958; RMC2004_5276; Color slide; Abraham Guillen (Box 19)
      - Men and women of Vicos winnowing barley together, 1958; RMC2004_5277; Color slide; Abraham Guillen (Box 19)
      - Communal winnowing work in Vicos, 1958; RMC2004_5278; Color slide; Abraham Guillen (Box 19)
      - Boy peasant in the corn harvest, 1958; RMC2004_5279; Color slide; Abraham Guillen (Box 19)
      - Vicos children helping with the harvest, 1958; RMC2004_5280; Color slide; Abraham Guillen (Box 19)
      - Drying grains, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5281; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Vicos landscape, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5282; Color slide; Abraham Guillen (Box 19)
      - Vicos landscape with road, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5283; Color slide; Abraham Guillen (Box 19)
      - Storing maize husks for fodder, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5284; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Storing maize husks beside a house for fodder, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5285; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Vicos harvest, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5286; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Vicos adobe house, 1952; RMC2004_5287; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Thrashing maize using horses, 1958; RMC2004_5288; Color slide; Abraham Guillen (Box 19)
      - Communal work in Quebrada Honda, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5289; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Communal work on a hill slope, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5290; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Children at the new school, 1958; RMC2004_5291; Color slide; Abraham Guillen (Box 19)
      - Inside Vicos' plaza (main square), circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5292; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Cornell - Peru Project apartment building in Vicos, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5293; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Vicos house, 1955, September 1955; RMC2004_5294; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Vicos house, 1951; RMC2004_5295; Color slide (Box 19)
        Adobe houses in Vicos, Ancash.
      - Terraced fields, Vicos, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5296; Color slide (Box 19)
      - The valley of Vicos, 1952; RMC2004_5297; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Women herding sheep and goats, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5298; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Vicos man and boy making fence posts, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5299; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Constructing buildings with brick, 1960; RMC2004_5300; Color slide (Box 19)
        Several men and boys laying bricks for multi-room building.
      - Building a small farm in Vicos, 1960; RMC2004_5301; Color slide (Box 19)
        Three young men laying adobe brick photographed against the sky.
      - Storing maize husks for fodder, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5302; Color slide (Box 19)
        Maize husks stored in between two poles beside a house.
      - Vicosina woman by hut with wool drying on hay, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5303; Color slide (Box 19)
        Peasant woman standing by two huts with wool drying on hay stacks nearby. Mountains in the distance.
      - Woman preparing pachamanca (?) over a fire, 1958; RMC2004_5304; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Vicosina woman grinding using a stone mortar, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5305; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Potato field, September 1955; RMC2004_5306; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Potato fields and hut, September 1955; RMC2004_5307; Color slide (Box 19)
      - School teachers' house, RMC2004_5308; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Buildings on Vicos' Plaza, RMC2004_5309; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Church and entrance to school, RMC2004_5310; Color slide (Box 19)
      - New school at Vicos, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5311; Color slide (Box 19)
      - The plaza of Vicos and landscape, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5312; Color slide (Box 19)
      - The school and the plaza of Vicos, 1958; RMC2004_5313; Color slide (Box 19)
      - View of Vicos, 1954; RMC2004_5314; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Trabajos de Rupublica (Republic works), 1954; RMC2004_5315; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Militia training at Vicos (?), circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5316; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Drying root crops, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5317; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Winowing cebada, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5318; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Sowing maize, 1955; RMC2004_5319; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Vicos, sector Chullan, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5320; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Thrashing quinua, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5321; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Vara traditional authorities, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5322; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Child shepards, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5323; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Fiesta de las Mercedes (The Mercedes Virgin's celebration): Wax ornaments for the procession., September 24, 1955; RMC2004_5324; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Procession during The Mercedes' celebration, September 24, 1955; RMC2004_5325; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Mercedes celebration at Vicos, September 24, 1955; RMC2004_5326; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Vicos plaza during The Mercedes Celebration, September 24, 1955; RMC2004_5327; Color slide (Box 19)
      - A priest during the Mercedes Celebration at Vicos, September 24, 1955; RMC2004_5328; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Vicosinos dancers and musicians, September 24, 1955; RMC2004_5329; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Vicosinos musicians at the door of the church, September 24, 1955; RMC2004_5330; Color slide (Box 19)
        The Mercedes Celebration, Vicos, 1955.
      - Offerings to The Mercedes Virgin, September 24, 1955; RMC2004_5331; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Vicosinos meet at The Mercedes celebration, September 24, 1955; RMC2004_5332; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Vicosina woman at the plaza during The Mercedes celebration, September 24, 1955; RMC2004_5333; Color slide (Box 19)
      - The octava, September 25, 1955; RMC2004_5334; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Cargo's house, September 1955; RMC2004_5335; Color slide (Box 19)
      - A procession at Vicos, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5336; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Vicosinos dancing, 1952; RMC2004_5337; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Palm Sunday celebration, 1951; RMC2004_5338; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Vicos fiesta: beef butchered at the Mayordomo's house (with Peruvian flag)., September 24, 1960; RMC2004_5339; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Vicos school boys, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5340; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Allan Holmberg and Vicos school boys, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5341; Color slide (Box 19)
      - New school at Vicos, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5342; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Santa River Valley (Callejon de Huaylas) near Vicos., circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5343; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Callejon de Huaylas, Huascaran peak in background., circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5344; Color slide (Box 19)
      - A path in Callejon de Huaylas, Cordillera Blanca in background., circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5345; Color slide (Box 19)
      - A town in Callejon de Huaylas, Huascaran peak in background., circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5346; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Town's plaza in Callejon de Huaylas, Cordillera Blanca in background., circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5347; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Marcara Village, a town neighbouring Vicos., circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5348; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Marcara's plaza (main square), circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5349; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Marcara's market, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5350; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Marcara's streets, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5351; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Selling anilinas (synthetic dyes) in Marcara., circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5352; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Saint Isidro's celebration, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5353; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Market scene in Marcara., circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5354; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Vicosinos at the market in Marcara, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5355; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Chat at the market, circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5356; Color slide (Box 19)
      - Selling hats at the market in Marcara., circa 1952-1962; RMC2004_5357; Color slide (Box 19)
    - Drawings and paintings
      - Sketch of Mayobamba village plan (Mapcase-folder 1)
      - Juan Victor's drawing (age 11) Quinto, Juan Victor, circa 1952-1962; Pencil (Box 30)
        A digital image of this item is available. Digital Image ID: RMC2004_5358
      - Victor Quinto (age 11), circa 1952-1962; Watercolor (Mapcase-folder 9)
      - Glicerio's pantings (age 10) Coleto, Glicerio, circa 1952-1962; Watercolor; 3 items (Mapcase-folder 9)
      - Glicerio's drawing (age 10), circa 1952-1962; Pencil (Box 30)
        A digital image of this item is available. Digital Image ID: RMC2004_5359
      - Juan Victor's drawing #2 (age 11), circa 1952-1962; Pencil (Box 30)
        A digital image of this item is available. Digital Image ID: RMC2004_5360
      - Juan Victor's drawing #3 (age 11), circa 1952-1962; Pencil (Box 30)
        A digital image of this item is available. Digital Image ID: RMC2004_5361
      - Germain's painting (age 12) Francisco, Germain, circa 1952-1962; Watercolor (Mapcase-folder 11)
        A digital image of this item is available. Digital Image ID: RMC2004_5362
      - Pablo's painting (age 10) Cruz, Pablo, circa 1952-1962; Watercolor (Mapcase-folder 9)
        A digital image of this item is available. Digital Image ID: RMC2004_5363
      - Paulino's painting (age 7) Gutierrez, Paulino, circa 1952-1962; Watercolor (Mapcase-folder 10)
        A digital image of this item is available. Digital Image ID: RMC2004_5364
      - Augustin's painting (age 16) Cruz, Augustin, circa 1952-1962; Watercolor (Mapcase-folder 9)
      - Additional drawings and paintings by Vicosino children, 4 folders (Box 30)
    - "Primitive Art in the Andes" (Mapcase-folder 9)
- Series II. Cornell Peru Project (Accession 2)
  The material in this series was part of an accession of Allan Holmberg's files received in the early 1980s. It complements the material in Series I. Some materials, such as field notebooks and publications, were incorporated into the first series to complete existing groups of materials. This series mostly contains correspondence and subject files relating the research conducted in Vicos and the management of the project.
  - A Short History of Vicos by Henry Dobyns (Box 18, Folder 30)
  - Historical documents-Vicos (Box 18, Folder 31)
  - Hacienda Vicos rent, 1950-1952 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Chronology of Vicos hacienda; Peruvians and Peruvian ministries related to Vicos (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Budget accounts, financial statements (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Vicos-project statements (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Vicos-financial statements (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Vicos accounts, 1954 (Box 18, Folder 32)
  - Progress report, CPP, 1952 (Box 18, Folder 33)
  - Progress reports, circa 1964-1965 (Box 18, Folder 34)
  - Reports, unpublished Cornell-Peru material, 1950s-early 1960s (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Purchase of fundo Vicos from the Sociedad Publica de Beneficencia de Huaraz, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - The Vicos Research Proposal, Allan Holmberg and Edward Suchman, 1956 (Box 18, Folder 35)
  - Proposal to Carnegie Corporation, May 1957 (Box 18, Folder 36)
  - Ford Foundation proposal, 1956-1957 (Box 18, Folder 37)
  - Grant proposal, "The Acculturation of Rural-Urban Migrants", 1961 (Box 18, Folder 38)
  - Holmberg-Lasswell collaboration (Box 18, Folder 39-40)
  - Correspondence and writings-Harold Lasswell, 1956-1957, 1964-1966; [Folders 1-2 of 3] (Box 18, Folder 41-42)
  - Correspondence and writings-Harold Lasswell, 1956-1957, 1964-1966; [Folder 3 of 3] (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Gary Vescelius correspondence, 1963-1965 (Box 18, Folder 43)
  - Administrative correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 18, Folder 44)
  - Correspondence, 1947-1949 (Box 18, Folder 45)
  - Correspondence (most with John Collier), 1949, 1954-1955 (Box 18, Folder 46)
  - Carnegie Corporation, 1952 (Box 18, Folder 47)
  - Correspondence-Vicos-school, 1953-1954 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence answered, 1954-1955 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - South American correspondence, 1948-1956 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Vicos correspondence, 1951-1954 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Peru correspondence, 1952-1957 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence-Lauriston Sharp, 1954 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Vicos correspondence, 1953, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - Vicos correspondence, 1952-1957 (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence, 1951-1955 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1953-1956 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence-Carlos Monge Medrano, 1954-1956 (Box 20, Folder 9-10)
  - Correspondence-Carlos Monge Medrano, 1950s (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence-Bill Mangin, 1951-1953, 1958-1959 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence-Rand McNally and Company, 1962 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Personal correspondence, 1960-1961 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1953-1955 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence-Mario Vazquez, 1949-1950 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence-Mario Vazquez, 1952-1963 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence-Humberto Ghersi Barrera, Mario Vazquez, 1949-1954 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence-Humberto Ghersi Barrera, 1949-1952 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Marcara photographs and notes sent to Humberto Ghersi Barrera, 1950 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence-Marshall T. Newman, 1955-1957 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence-Manuel D. Velasco Nunez, 1952 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Inventories and accounts-William Blanchard, 1956-1957 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence-William Blanchard, 1953-1955 (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence-William Blanchard, Manuel D. Velasco Nunez, 1953 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence-William Blanchard, Marshall T. Newman and Manuel D. Velasco Nunez, 1956 (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence-John L. Kennedy (Rand Corporation), 1956-1957 (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, Summer 1956 (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, 1958 (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, 1956-1960 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1961-1965 (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - Copies of Dobyns' letters to others, 1960-1961 (Box 20, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence-Henry Dobyns, 1958-1963 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence-Henry Dobyns; Andean Research Program report; Cornell-Peru agreement, 1960 (Box 20, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence-Henry Dobyns, Cara Richards Dobyns; project expenses, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence-Henry Dobyns, 1961-1962 (Box 20, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence-Henry Dobyns, 1964-1965 (Box 20, Folder 30-32)
  - United States Agency for International Development, 1963 (Box 20, Folder 33)
  - Notes on collaboration with Parke Davis (Box 20, Folder 34)
  - Reports-Abner Montalvo Vidal, 1955 (Box 20, Folder 35)
  - Speech given at the "Centro Cultural Ancash," by Montalvo, 1955 (Box 20, Folder 36)
  - Vicos-education, 1950s (Box 20, Folder 37)
  - Education Vicos by Pedro Ortiz, 1955 (Box 20, Folder 38)
  - School questionnaire by Ortiz, 1954 (Box 20, Folder 39)
  - Cornell Methodology Project-questionnaires and codes, 1953 (Box 20, Folder 40)
  - "Code: Vicos Survey of Westernization"; Vicos questionnaire-Methodology Project, 1953 (Box 20, Folder 41)
  - Norman Pava [contains photograph] (Box 20, Folder 42)
  - Attitudinal change (Box 20, Folder 43)
  - Trial marriage (Box 20, Folder 44)
  - Parasitology study (Box 20, Folder 45)
  - Allen and Newman studies in Vicos (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Andean Research Program reports, 1959-1960, 1962 (Box 20, Folder 46)
  - Shashall-field notes (Box 20, Folder 47)
  - Journal of Hilario Gonzales-Vicos, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 48)
  - Road maps, 18 maps (Box 14)
  - Map by Humberto Ghersi Barrera, 1952 (Mapcase-folder 8)
  - Maps, 1932, 1939 (Box 20, Folder 49)
  - Village of Huaylas, map (Box 20, Folder 50)
  - Sample for Photographic Housing Survey of Vicos, 1955 (Box 20, Folder 51)
  - Surveys and instructions (Box 20, Folder 52)
  - Vicos, Survey Sanitario, [Folders 1-5 of 8] (Box 20, Folder 53-57)
  - Vicos, Survey Sanitario, [Folders 6-8 of 8] (Box 21, Folder 1-3)
  - Survey sanitario, 1954 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Vicos questionnaires, survey results, census information (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Vicos-census, 1959 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Census codes, Marcara and Vicos (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Acculturation indices in Vicos, 1956 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Un Cuestionario para un Censo Industrial del Callejon de Huaylas y del Valle del Santa (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Vicos-school building and construction, 1953 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Vicos-education, school building, 1950s (Box 22, Folder 11-12)
  - School lunch, 1955 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Peruvians views on Vicos and Indian studies, 1952, 1959 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Reactions of Peruvian communities to Vicos activities, 1958 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Interviews with officials of the Vicos region, 1951-1952 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence-Vicosinos, 1955-1956 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Vicos research-various correspondence, 1954-1965 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Vicos-archeology, Federico Kauffmann Doig, Chopijirca, 1955-1956 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Questionnaire given by Martinez to potato experiment members, 1955 (Box 21, Folder 15-16)
  - Summaries of NSP experimentation, 1952 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - New seed potatoes, 1954-1955 (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Agricultural credit-Vicos (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Agricultural reports, 1959, undated (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Diagrams of societal structure (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Vicos-religion-Declamation for the LOA (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - Vicos-army, 1950, 1956 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Animal husbandry-Indian-Peru, 1951 (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - Research-Paul Doughty, 1960 (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - Archeological legislation-Peru, 1953 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Vicos-milk distribution, 1955-1956 (Box 21, Folder 24)
  - Vicos-public health, 1956 (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Vicos-methodology, 1954-1955 (Box 21, Folder 25)